export const LEATHERWORKA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. What substance comes out of the skin during sweating?",
A: "Hair",
B: "Fat",
C: "Flesh",
D: "Moisture",
answer: "D. Moisture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following is a leather container?",
A: "Appliqué",
B: "Fringes",
C: "Quiver",
D: "Thong",
answer: "C. Quiver",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Leather patterning as a result of stamping with metal dies is referred to as",
A: "antiqued.",
B: "embossed.",
C: "morocco.",
D: "patent.",
answer: "B. Embossed",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Select from the following a meterial that can be cut, glued, carved, sewn, dyed and painted.",
A: "Fabric",
B: "Leather",
C: "Leatherette",
D: "Rawhide",
answer: "B. Leather",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which description best suits a properly tanned chamois leather?",
A: "Soft as cloth and will hold water like cloth",
B: "Soft and fragile when soaked in water on Very soft, flexible, warm and water resistant",
C: "Very soft, slippery, thin and water repellent",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "A. Soft as cloth and will hold water like cloth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The tanning process that promotes the pliability of leather is",
A: "beaming.",
B: "buffing.",
C: "conditioning,",
D: "fat liquoring.",
answer: "D. Fat liquoring",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Skins are degreased with",
A: "brine.",
B: "heat.",
C: "lacquer.",
D: "paraffin.",
answer: "B. Heat",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Fast dried skins become",
A: "flexible and soft.",
B: "hard and brittle.",
C: "soft and brittle.",
D: "tough and flexible.",
answer: "B. Hard and brittle",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following animals produces a hide?",
A: "Alligator",
B: "Buffalo",
C: "Goat",
D: "Fox",
answer: "B. Buffalo",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The skin turns into a glue-like material if the process of drying is",
A: "by aeration.",
B: "rapid.",
C: "slow.",
D: "under shade.",
answer: "C. Slow",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Some post-tanning procedures are",
A: "dyeing and liming.",
B: "liming and pickling.",
C: "Bat pickling and shaving.",
D: "shaving and dyeing.",
answer: "D. Shaving and dyeing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Shoes that are too tight produce",
A: "boil.",
B: "bunions.",
C: "rashes.",
D: "wen.",
answer: "B. Bunions",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In fat liquoring, the skin is impregnated with",
A: "brine.",
B: "lime.",
C: "oil.",
D: "water.",
answer: "C. Oil",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The smaller type of a grommet is the",
A: "D-ring.",
B: "eyelet.",
C: "O-ring.",
D: "stud.",
answer: "B. Eyelet",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The tool used for spacing and boring holes simultaneously is the",
A: "revolving punch.",
B: "round drive punch.",
C: "swivel knife.",
D: "tonging chisel.",
answer: "A. Revolving punch",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of thé following leathers is named after an animal?",
A: "Cabretta",
B: "Chamois",
C: "Cape",
D: "Morocco",
answer: "A. Cabretta",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The base of an article is protected with the",
A: "grommet.",
B: "piping.",
C: "ring.",
D: "stud.",
answer: "D. Stud",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Leather remains relatively soft if it is",
A: "heat-dried.",
B: "oven-dried.",
C: "room-dried,",
D: "sun-dried.",
answer: "C. Room-dried",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Designs made by boring through the leather are",
A: "pecling and carving.",
B: "perforating and scratching.",
C: "stitching and peeling.",
D: "stitching and perforating.",
answer: "B. Perforating and scratching",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Leather must be moistened before",
A: "assembling,",
B: "cutting.",
C: "stamping.",
D: "stitching.",
answer: "C. Stamping",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is sometimes used to join pieces of leather permanently?",
A: "Buckle",
B: "D-ring",
C: "Eyelet",
D: "Swivel",
answer: "D. Swivel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The main objective of tanning is to make hides and skins resistant to",
A: "bacteria.",
B: "heat.",
C: "moulding.",
D: "tearing.",
answer: "A. Bacteria",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Identify a slit-making tool from the following.",
A: "A glover’s needle",
B: "Pair of scissors",
C: "The tonging chisel",
D: "The stitch-marker.",
answer: "C. The tonging chisel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is a finishing process in leatherwork?",
A: "Burnishing",
B: "Cutting",
C: "Glueing",
D: "Sewing",
answer: "A. Burnishing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Staking leather is a technique of",
A: "moving strips up and down in a solution.",
B: "pulling and softening leather over a tool.",
C: "working liquids out of skins.",
D: "working skins in solution.",
answer: "B. Pulling and softening leather over a tool",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Textures in leather are obtained by",
A: "glazing, buffing and graining.",
B: "keeping them in damp places.",
C: "rubbing and drying in the sun.",
D: "stamping, embossing and fraying.",
answer: "D. Stamping, embossing and fraying",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. How many layers has a pelt?",
A: "One",
B: "Two",
C: "Three",
D: "Four",
answer: "C. Three",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In leather production, lime and wood ash are used when",
A: "curing hides.",
B: "removing hair.",
C: "stuffing leather.",
D: "tawing skins.",
answer: "B. Removing hair",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following processes proceeds thonging after measuring and drawing lines?",
A: "Making grooves",
B: "Punching slit holes",
C: "Sewing with needles",
D: "Sewing with machines",
answer: "B. Punching slit holes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Cordovan is a leather obtained from",
A: "cow hide.",
B: "horse hide.",
C: "pig skin.",
D: "snake skin.",
answer: "B. Horse hide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Fittings are used in leatherwork for",
A: "binding and stitching.",
B: "decorating and assembling.",
C: "finishing and sewing.",
D: "sewing and assembling.",
answer: "B. Decorating and assembling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Clapettes are suitable fasteners for",
A: "cases.",
B: "pockets.",
C: ". purses.",
D: "wallets.",
answer: "D. Wallets",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. To avoid thick joints at the edges, the leathers are",
A: "skived.",
B: "split.",
C: "stapled.",
D: "tooled.",
answer: "A. Skived",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. 'Which of the following processes immediately comes after dehairing?",
A: "Fleshing",
B: "Liming",
C: "‘Pickling",
D: "Salting",
answer: "A. Fleshing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Grommets as attachments are similar to.",
A: "dee-rings.",
B: "eyelets.",
C: "press-stud,",
D: "rivets.",
answer: "B. Eyelets",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Leather from buffalo is most suitable for",
A: "book jackets.",
B: "clothing.",
C: "lining.",
D: "shoe soles.",
answer: "D. Shoe soles",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following is a major characteristic of the butt?",
A: "Tensility",
B: "Thickness",
C: "Softness",
D: "Strength",
answer: "D. Strength",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The following are methods of assembling parts of a leather except",
A: "braiding.",
B: "lacing.",
C: "stitching.",
D: "thonging.",
answer: "A. Braiding",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A skin is converted into leather when",
A: "alum is spread over it.",
B: "it is put into lime solution.",
C: "it is soaked in tannin.",
D: "it is soaked in warm water.",
answer: "C. It is soaked in tannin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The stitch marker is a tool for",
A: "creating stitch points.",
B: "creating serrated edges.",
C: "enlarging stitch holes.",
D: "making holes at the seam.",
answer: "A. Creating stitch points",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]